What I'd like to talk about is really the biggest problems in the world.
De lo que les quiero hablar es, cuáles son realmente los problemas más grandes del mundo.
I'm not going to talk about "The Skeptical Environmentalist" --
No les voy a hablar del "Ambientalista Escéptico"
probably that's also a good choice.
probablemente también un buen tema.
(Laughter)
(Risas)
But I am going talk about: what are the big problems in the world?
De lo que les voy a hablar es, ¿cuáles son los grandes problemas en el mundo?
And I must say, before I go on, I should ask every one of you
Y debo decir, antes de seguir con esto, debo pedir a cada uno de ustedes
to try and get out pen and paper
que intente sacar lápiz y papel
because I'm actually going to ask you to help me to look at how we do that.
porque realmente les voy a pedir que me ayuden a examinar cómo hacemos esto.
So get out your pen and paper.
Entonces, saquen lápiz y papel.
Bottom line is, there is a lot of problems out there in the world.
A fin de cuentas, hay muchísimos problemas en el mundo.
I'm just going to list some of them.
Sólo voy a listar algunos de ellos.
There are 800 million people starving.
Hay 800 millones de personas muriendo de hambre.
There's a billion people without clean drinking water.
Hay mil millones de personas sin agua potable.
Two billion people without sanitation.
Dos mil millones de personas sin saneamiento.